# TOM STROTHER SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville, TN



573,999,6990

tstrotheriv@gmail.com

tstrotheriv.github.io/

**in** linkedin.com/in/tomstrother/

Having founded two tech startups and being directly involved with building teams in my past work history, I truly understand a team's value. I know how crucial it is to have a calm and positive mindset in all situations, no matter the circumstance.

In the Software and Tech industry, continually learning and adapting is required. Over the past 15 years, I have self-taught myself all aspects of the entertainment industry. My start came as an audio engineer at the Conservatory of Recording arts but learned the skills required to not only operate but ultimately lead teams in Video, Lighting, Live Streaming, conference planning, and project management.

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

JAVASCRIPT •GIT/GITHUB •REACT •AFRAME (VR) •HTML CLOUDINARY •CSS •PYTHON

•BOOTSTRAP •DJANGO w/ ORM •REACTSTRAP DJANGO Rest

•POSTMAN

#### EDUCATION

Nashville Software School Full-stack Web Development Bootcamp

#### TECHNICAL EDUCATION

## Software Developer

## Nashville Software School | Apr 2020 - present

NSS is an immersive and highly focused 6 month software development program learning JavaScript, React, Python, and Django. Our cohort was the first one to be on-boarded and graduate 100% remote.

#### **CLASS PROJECTS:**

Welcome to Nashville: Welcome to Nashville is a group project with a single page web application that allows Nashville tourists to create a "To Do" itinerary utilizing HTML5 and CSS.

Technology used: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript ES6, JSON, Bootstrap

Arboretum: Arboretum is a "command line interface" group project built using Python. We were able to build a menu with guided options to create "habitats" and then be able to add animals to the habitats. We added a layer of complexity by only allowing animals with certain habitat requirements to be added to those areas. We then created a menu item to "print" a report of all the habitats and animals in those areas.

Technology used: Python CLI

Nutshell: : Nutshell was a group

project where we created a user dashboard with a login and authentication. The dashboard featured a Chat Feed between users, To Do list, and a News Articles section populated by an API.

Technology used: JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3, JSON-Server, Postman, RESTful

Github: https://github.com/nss-cohort-40/c40-keahua-arboretum-da beach combers

#### CAPSTONE PROJECTS

## MyListing360 VR React App (Frontend - React)

MyListing 360 is a resource for Real Estate Agents and Brokerages as a response to the COVID Pandemic. Fewer Agents and Buyers are willing to visit homes in person due to restrictions so Agents have tried to come up with creative Solutions for showing listings. MyListing360 is a great simple solution to this problem by providing a resource for Agents to be build and share immersive Virtual Reality Tours in only minutes using 360 images of the home.

Technology Used: React, A-Frame, Cloudinary, Reactstrap, Google Analytics, HTML, CSS, JSX, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Premier Pro

https://github.com/tstrotherIV/MyListing360

## MasterPlan (Backend - Django)

MasterPlan is a project management system specific to the corporate events Industry. It provides every field specific to events eliminating the need to build every to-do as you would in other generic management system templates.

Technology Used: Django Full Stack Application, Bootstrap

https://github.com/tstrotherIV/masterplan

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Tech Founder and CEO

## Live It Now (Live Streaming) | Feb 2011 - Present

#### An event tech startup

- Built well-established referral client network and worked closely with executives and project managers to identify and execute on their vision and goals
- Learned HTTP live streaming protocol standards and workflow to deliver live streaming for entertainment and corporate broadcast needs. Built single page websites with WordPress and SquareSpace to host events
- Oversaw all management and project management of travel logistics, securing contract staff, and venue staff to successfully deliver events on time and within budget. Creatively problem solved client changes, staffing issues, equipment issues, transportation issues, etc.

#### Tech Founder and CEO

## RoundHound | Feb 2015 - Present

Virtual Reality Tour tech start-up for the real estate industry

Established clients through networking, maintained professional relationships with local agents and brokers, then on-boarded clients to the system with user training and account creation.

- Conceptualized and designed innovative VR platform and contracted with a team of software developers to build out application
- Established relationships with local real estate agents and brokers to onboard to platform
- Built estimates, proposals, invoices, and balanced budgets using Custom excel docs, Google Drive Docs and QuickBooks Online.

## Project Manager and Director of Development

## Gary Musick Productions | Sep 2018 - Apr 2020

Full-service corporate and entertainment management company.

- Managed review process for proposals and executed concurrent large-scale projects (\$15,000 to \$400,000) from concept for many
  established known national brands; adapted to expenses above defined budget by creatively adjusting schedule, finding production
  substitutions, and negotiating lower costs
- Led all hiring and in-person training of production staff, crew, and subcontractors for our execution teams.
- Built monthly and weekly schedules, including goals and specific checkpoints to ensure on time delivery and within approved budget
  for production team to provide greater visibility and accountability to teams due to overlapping projects. Leveraged Google Docs and
  Teamwork software.

#### **Production Manager**

# Nashville Event Lighting | Jun 2008 - Oct 2013

- Executive Production Manager and Designer responsible for the design and execution of all events
- Successfully managed 25+ events in one weekend during CMA fest around Nashville. Average weeks had 10+ events regularly with crew of 3-10 technicians on each job
- Developed and delivered monthly in-person training programs for all new hires on equipment and safety requirements

### Director of Media

## First United Methodist Church | Feb 2014 - Jun 2018

- Designed, budgeted, and contracted a \$180,000+ audio visual upgrade to modern standards in high definition. Designed and installed a live streaming system for weekly broadcast similar to a TV broadcast
- Re-designed and built company websites using WordPress and Adobe Creative Suite and managed social media sites.
- Recruited and led 20 volunteers to execute weekly services and events, provided ongoing training programs in audio, video and streaming, and
  fostered supportive and encouraging collaborative work environment